Cole Johnson

Software Developer

541-588-2911 | CBurnJohnson@gmail.com | Beaverton, OR 97006

Portfolio: cburnjohnson.com | github.com/CBurnJohnson | linkedin.com/in/cburnjohnson |

PROFILE

I am a passionate Full Stack Developer with industry experience building web applications using Agile methodologies. The stack I enjoy the most developing with is the MERN stack. I love the flexibility of JavaScript, but my passion for development doesn't stem from one language or stack. My passion comes from the immense amount of learning opportunities that arise each project you start.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, C#, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS.

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Node, Express, .NET, Django, Bootstrap, Materialize.

Databases: MongoDB, SQL Server, MySQL.

Version Control: Git, Azure DevOps.

Technical: REST APIs.

Methodologies/Design: Agile, Scrum, Model-View-Controller

General: Problem Solving, Project Management, Microsoft Office, Critical Thinking, Time Management,

Adaptability, Attention to Detail, Self-Motivated.

PROJECTS

Phone Book - MERN Full Stack Application

Technology Used: MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS, and JavaScript.

- Application that stores the user's personal/professional contacts built with the MERN stack.
- Complete registration and login system with validation.
 - Implemented JSON Web Tokens to help with authentication.
- Backend API created with Express, supports CRUD functionalities for contacts.
- Authenticated users are able to filter through contacts, as well as add, delete, edit, or update contacts.

Pokedex - React Application

Technology Used: React. JavaScript. and CSS.

- React Web application that emulates a Pokedex using Pokeapi.co's Pokemon API.
 - Mainly built with React hooks, and functional components.
- Implemented pagination, and custom CSS styling for the application.
- Displays a list of twenty pokemon on each page with details/moves about each pokemon.
 - Has access to over 700 unique pokemon.

LoL Summoners - React Application

Technology Used: React, JavaScript, and CSS.

- Application that lets users look up there League of Legends account information.
- Displays the searched account summoner level, summoner icon, queue ranks, and recent match history.
 - Consumes Riot Game's League, Match, and Summoner APIs.
- Implemented React's Context API to manage the application's state easier.
- Uses React-Router to help with state when redirecting from the homepage to the account details page.

IT Work Orders - React Application

Technology Used: React, Redux, JavaScript, Materialize Css, and JSON Server.

- Logging/Tracking application for IT work orders built with React, Redux, and JSON Server.
- Admin's are able to create new work orders for a technician, add new technicians, and view a list of current technicians.
- Logs keep track of what time they are updated, and by which technician.
- Built the user interface using the CSS framework Materialize CSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Prosper I.T. Consulting, Portland, OR. - Intern Software Developer

March 2019 - June 2019

- Developed a DataScrape and Construction Management application.
 - o Implemented a directions application within the DataScrape project using a MapQuest API.
 - Project Summaries: <u>DataScrape</u> | <u>Construction Management</u>
- Utilized Agile methodology Scrum for workflow and project management to increase team productivity.
 - Attended daily stand-up meetings with the development team to coordinate project priorities.
- Trained under Senior Developer to become proficient working on front-end, and back-end stories with a team.

Candy Tyme, Eugene, OR - Assistant Manager

September 2017 - November 2018

- Trained all newly hired employees on day to day tasks that needs to be done.
 - o Coached employees on upselling techniques to improve overall sales of the store.
- Implemented employee of the month system based on employee sales to improve team morale.
- Performed weekly inventory counts, and supply orders for needed products.
- Responsible for handling money, and completing money drops at the bank.
- Participated in conference calls with the other Candy Tyme store managers, and owner of the stores.

Subway, Bend, OR - Shift Manager

October 2016 - August 2017

- Became the main closer for the store, and was assigned to train employees on closing duties.
- Solved any problems that came up during my shift which included customer, team member, and shipment problems.
- Happily cooperated with team members to construct sandwiches efficiently.
 - Designated team members to specific stations to help with organization during rush hours.

EDUCATION

The Tech Academy, Portland, OR. - Software Developer Certificate

November 2018 - May 2019

The Tech Academy is an intensive software developer boot camp that has over 600 hours of hands on learning. I learned the fundamentals of development, as well as the most common web development languages, and frameworks. Some of the languages, and frameworks I learned are C#, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Django, Bootstrap, and .NET.

Central Oregon Community College, Bend, OR. - Associate of Science

September 2014 - June 2016

Completed a variety of courses during my time at this institute that included Anthropology, Psychology, Calculus, and Computer Science. Associate of Science in Chemistry.